

vbhat@ncsu.edu https://bhatvivek.com github.com/VivekBhat linkedin.com/in/vivek-bhat

SUMMARY

AWS Certified Developer and Solutions Architect with experience designing, developing and deploying AI and Big Data solutions in an Agile environment. Avid clean coder and adept at rapid prototyping for fast turnaround times in POCs.

EDUCATION

North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC, USA

August 2016 – December 2017

MS in Computer Science

Jamia Millia University, New Delhi, India

June 2012 - July 2016

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics and Communication Engineering

CORE TECHNICAL COMPETENCIES

Programming Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, Angular, Python, Flask, Ansible, NodeJS, SQL

Tools & Utilities AWS, Azure, Spring Boot, Rally, Git, Docker, Elasticsearch, Logstash, Kibana, Maven

Operating Systems Linux, Unix, Windows, WSL, Macintosh

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Intel, Hillsboro, Oregon, Software Development Engineer

January 2018 – To Date

Nov 2020 – To Date

Project: LTD Microservice Commons **Role:** Backend Software Developer

• Developing a scalable Spring Boot based microservice to submit Spark jobs in a Hadoop ecosystem

- Refactored LDAP and Kerberos authentication microservice to be used as a dependency from an internal Artifactory
- Created a CI/CD pipeline with 100% test coverage built for customers using Java, Docker, Gradle and Azure Pipelines

Project: Centralized Data Repository

Mar 2020 – Nov 2020

Role: Big Data Engineer

- Developed and improved a centralized data lake that holds datasets across Intel to accelerate data analysis solution
- Modernized data transfer between different systems with 3x increase in throughput using Apache NiFi
- Implemented enterprise grade fault tolerance, monitoring and flexibility for multiple datatypes and data sources

Project: Retail Promotion Analytics (RPA)

Jan 2019 – Mar 2020

Role: Full Stack Developer

- Designed and developed RPA UI and APIs, integrated user authorizations, sign-ups and sign-ins with AWS Cognito.
- Lead and trained a team of interns, contract workers and staff members on how to make minor updates and changes.
- Successfully released the product before due date and accommodated 25% increase in scope during iteration.

Project: Intel Saffron, Rest APIs and Infrastructure

Jan 2018 – Oct 2018

Role: Software Developer

- Developed API's in Java and Python to facilitate REST querying and processing
- Enabling concurrency and 2x faster results in client environments with quick POCs
- Automated the process of conventional installation by creating a pipeline using Ansible, Docker, Docker Swarm and Bash scripting which reduced the installation time by 50% and removed any margin of human error

Intel, Cary, North Carolina, SDE Summer Intern

May 2017 – Aug 2017

- Developed Intel Saffron's Java REST API, encapsulating unique security protocols and complex API classification and recommendation, leveraging an AI product and reducing the time to POC's.
- The tool enabled 10x faster API calls and provided simpler and easy to use rest API calls for the client user.

ADDITIONAL PROJECTS

Personal Portfolio, uses Angular, GitHub Actions for CI/CD, Karma for testing

https://bhatvivek.com

Personal secure portfolio/website hosted on GitHub pages with CI/CD for testing, building and deploying the application

Serverless REST APIs, uses AWS API Gateway, Lambda, Dynamo DB, NodeJS

git.io/JfGEJ

Developed serverless restful webservices with Lambda functions operating on AWS Dynamo DB database

LEADERSHIP AND VOLUNTEER SERVICE

- Organized multiple socio-cultural events at Intel and was board member of multiple Employee Resource Groups
- Served as the President of IEEE JMI Student Branch and IEEE JMI Computer Society (2015-2016)